

105 Johnston Ave. Toronto. Ontario

□ (647) 292-4223 | ■ gabechan@alumni.uwaterloo.ca | 回 gabecchan | 🛅 gabecchan

Summary_

Current Site Reliability Engineer at start-up company Kasa. 7+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and computer hacking/security. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises

Skills

DevOpsJira Premium, Confluence, BluePrints, VS Code, GitHub Enterprise, Jenkins, OpenShift, Ansible, JFrog Artifactory, MicroFocus UFT,

MicroFocus LoadRunner Enterprise 2021, DataDog

Technology Azure, Linux, Windows Servers, Mainframe, SQL Server, Oracle, ETL, Virtual Machines (VMs), SOAP/REST APIs

ProductivityMural, Draw.io, Office 365 including MS Teams, MS Forms, MS Streams, MS Bookings, Power Automate, Power BI, SharePoint 2010, SharePoint Online

Work Experience

Suncor Remote / Mississauga, Ontario

Manager, DevOps June 2020 - Present

- Head of DevOps, driving a digital transformation to create a DevOps mindset & culture, adoption of CI/CD toolsets, and measurement of Key DevOps metrics
- costs transformation from a project to product, Provisioned an easily managable hybrid infrastructure(Amazon AWS + On-premise) utilizing IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible, Packer and Terraform.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on CircleCl for containerized applications using Docker, AWS ECR and Rancher.
- Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of the Machine Learning based Fashion Tagging API SaaS product with the micro-services architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js Koa and in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Deployed a centralized logging environment (ELK, Filebeat, CloudWatch, S3) which gather log data from docker containers and AWS resources.
- Deployed a centralized monitoring environment(Grafana, InfluxDB, CollectD) which gather system metrics as well as docker run-time metrics.

Suncor Remote / Mississauga, Ontario

MANAGER, QUALITY MANAGEMENT

May 2019 - June 2020

- Quality Management practice lead of 50-60 resources across a \$300M portfolio of technology projects
- Created the assessment, roadmap and recommendation to transition towards a new approach using Quality Engineering
- Suncor lead for the indigenous testing student internship program and transitioned the quality management leadership team to use Agile Kanban boards
- Developed a resource allocation and utilization reporting solution using SharePoint & Power BI that was leveraged by other managers in the department

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

OUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST - DOWNSTREAM & TECHNICAL TESTING

Oct 2015 - May 2019

- Accountable for delivery quality on all downstream technology projects through quality management (QM) processes and by building a blended team of 30+ quality management resources
- Stood up and chaired the QM technical committee, responsible for driving innovation, utilization, and technical direction for QM tools across the enterprise
- Drove innovation through initiatives such as a quality management technical capability assessment and roadmap for QM Tools, Proof of Concept for agile tools like MicroFocus ALM Octane, and an upgrade of MicroFocus Performance Centre to a cloud supported version

Suncor Mississauga, Ontario

QUALITY MANAGEMENT TEST COORDINATOR (CONTRACT)

July 2011 - Sept 2015

- Quality Management program lead for a modernization program and accountable for resource training & staffing, quality governance and for coordination with program and project managers
- Coordinated Quality Management for projects such as the Retail Associate Intranet site upgrade to SharePoint 2010, Microsoft Dynamics AX version upgrade, Fuel Pricing Application upgrade and the POS Settlement application upgrade from Mainframe. Other projects include SAP Biller Direct, Everbridge and a Turnaround Safety and Productivity Solution in the Oil Sands

CIBC - Remote Banking and Shared Services

Toronto, Ontario

Fraud Test Consultant (Contract)

Feb 2010 - July 2011

 Accoutable for several fraud testing initiatives and created a new estimating model to forecast testing work efforts & costs for new fraud project initiatives CIBC Retail Markets Toronto, Ontario

VISA DEBIT: UAT TEST MANAGER (CONTRACT)

Feb 2009 - Jan 2010

• Successfully managed and delivered the User Acceptance Test (UAT) across multiple business groups as part of the launch of the first VISA Debit product into the Canadian marketplace

• Coordinated program testing across tests for card issuance, point-of-sale transactions, settlement and reconciliation, disputes & charge backs and loyalty program enrollment & fulfillment

Accenture Toronto, Ontario

TEST CONSULTANT (CONTRACT)

Nov 2008 - Dec 2008

· Developed a test data strategy and served as a subject matter expertise to support existing testing initiatives

Accenture Toronto, Ontario

FINANCIAL SERVICES - MULTIPLE ROLES

Sept 2003 - Oct 2008

- Project Manager Concurrently managed three AML projects across a team of 18 on initiatives related to personal credit products, vendor interface integrations and data migration into the enterprise AML datawarehouse
- Development Lead Led a five person team that automated the transformation and data movement for a Basel II regulatory capital calculation engine using mainframe JCL jobs, Zeke, DataStage and DataStage TX tools
- Business Analyst Lead Delivered business requirements for a retail credit card adjudication system that created a consolidated enterprise-wide customer profile to assess the products that best meet the customer's financial needs
- Test Lead Accountable for quality on projects related to small business credit adjudication, retail credit cards, inbound marketing integration with call centres, Cognos and SAS reporting, and a Basel data warehouse

Additional Experience Canada & US

CO-OP & INTERNSHIPS

1997 - 2002

· Marketing and technology roles at Microsoft Canada, Bell Canada, Cisco Systems, Dofasco, Delano Technology Corp, and Aird & Berlis LLP

Education_

Schulich School of Business, York University

Toronto, Ontario

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

2011 - 2014

MBA Games 2015 Champions, MBA Games 2014 participant

University of Waterloo
HONOURS BACHELOR OF APPLIED SCIENCE: SYSTEMS DESIGN ENGINEERING

Waterloo, Ontario

Economics Minor, Management Science Option

Hamilton, Ontario

Hillfield Strathallan College
Ontario Secondary School Diploma

1982 - 1998

Courses & Certifications

Mar 2021 Microsoft, Azure Al Fundamentals (Certified)

Toronto, Ontario

Feb 2021 **John Hopkins University**, A Crash Course in Data Science

Toronto, Ontario

Oct 2019 Microsoft, Azure Fundamentals (Certified)

Toronto, Ontario

Sept 2018 Disciplined Agile Consortium, Disciplined Agile Delivery (DA 101)

Calgary, Alberta